(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.1",
"generated_at": "2026-08-09T02:01:01.199980",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.6-flash",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
ハイ！ハイ！
Hey! Hey!
寒寒い夜の
On a freezing cold night's
帳 凍る言葉
veil, brushing off frozen words,
受け流して
slipping past them,
彗星を待っていた
I was waiting for a comet.
光には遠い
With a heart far removed
心で
from the light,
それでも輝きへと
even so, towards the brilliance
手を伸ばしたい
I want to reach out my hand.
そうそれには
Yes, for that,
暴れる夢が居たい
a raging dream wants to stay.
今は 今は名もなき
Right now, right now, an unnamed
花いざないの蕾だと
bud inviting flowers,
この世の嵐を
enduring the storms of this world,
耐えながら描くよ
I'll paint my future
情熱は絶たぬままで
with passion never extinguished.
泣きそうな時は泣いてしまえ
When you feel like crying, just cry it all out.
それが未来拓く魁となれ
Let that become the pioneer opening up the future!
瞳の温度は
The warmth in your eyes
上がることになるから
is bound to rise,
無駄になんかならない
so none of it will ever go to waste.
泣きそうな時は泣いてしまえ
When you feel like crying, just cry it all out.
今日はそんな日もあると笑って
Laugh it off, saying "today is just one of those days."
涙と混ぜ希望を
Mix your tears with hope,
そんな感じ
something like that—
華麗に制圧する前哨戦
a prelude to splendidly conquering it all!
離すなよ 虎視眈々
Don't let go, watching like a hawk
焦らし散らして 倍返勝
Teasing relentlessly, winning with double payback
功を焦らず 隙を狙わず 負けたくない 勝つしかない 1 2 3
Don't rush success, don't wait for a gap, I gotta win, 1 2 3!
ひとつじゃない いくつも 願い叶えたい
Not just one, I want to make so many wishes come true
遥かな地平 やっとの彗星
Across the distant horizon, a long-awaited comet
叫びへと変わる祈り
Prayers turning into a scream
それなら届きそうだ
If so, it feels like it will reach
掴んでみせ それから
I'll grab it, and after that
知らない夢を見よう
Let me dream a dream I've never known
されど されど 名も無き花の 胸の誇りには
And yet, in the pride within the heart of an nameless flower
この世の何より 尊いと思うよ
I believe it's more precious than anything else in this world
誰も 誰も 主役じゃなくても 我思う 故の自分
Even if nobody is the main character, I think, therefore I am
泣いちゃった分だけ 僕よ たくましく もっと もっと なんて欲張りかい？
Just as much as I cried, grow stronger, my self... "More, more", is that too greedy?
欲張りじゃない 願いだ 願いの強さが 七色の道で
It's not greed, it's a wish—the strength of that wish on a rainbow path
泣いちゃった分だけ 僕よ たくましく 唯一無二 魁となれ
Just as much as I cried, grow stronger, my self... Become the one and only pioneer!
浮世 浮き世を 最悪の野望に乗って 羨ましく咲かせよ 心
Riding on the ultimate ambition through this fleeting world, make your heart bloom envied by all!
泣きそうなときは 泣いてしまえ それが 未来 開花 魁となれ
When you feel like crying, just cry it out—let that bloom into the future and become the pioneer!
瞳の温度は 上がり続けるよ
The temperature in my eyes keeps rising
咲き誇れるよ もう一歩
I can bloom in full glory, just one more step
羨ましく咲かせよ 心
Make your heart bloom envy-worthily!
ハイ！ ハイ！
Oi! Oi!
サンキュー！
Thank you!
諦めかけた 本当の言葉を
The true words I almost gave up on,
生きてゆく鼓動を
the heartbeat to keep living,
痛みながら ただ 消えぬように
while in pain, just so they won't fade away...
まだ 息をしたい 理由があるの
I still have a reason why I want to breathe.
幸せだけを選んでいたって
Even if I only chose happiness,
先は見えない
I can't see what lies ahead.
過ぎ去った今を 仕方ないなんて
Saying "it can't be helped" about the past that slid by...
消せればいいけど
It'd be nice if I could just erase it.
嘘で
With lies,
塗り重ねられる 夢じゃない
it's not a dream that can be painted over.
諦めかけた 本当の言葉を
The true words I almost gave up on,
生きてゆく鼓動を
the heartbeat to keep living...
闇に迷うのは ひとつじゃない 道があるから
Losing my way in the dark is because there isn't just one path.
賭けて 求めて また傷が増えて
Gambling, searching, and gaining more wounds again,
すべて捨て去れば
if I throw everything away,
痛みなどない
there won't be any pain.
でも 立ち尽くすだけじゃ
But just standing still...
見られない 明日があるの
there's a tomorrow I won't be able to see.
満ち足りた人が
A satisfied person—
いつか訪れると思っていた
I thought one would visit someday.
誰も同じと
Thinking everyone is the same,
独りを消しては
erasing my loneliness,
目を背けた
I turned my eyes away.
喉につかえた言葉を飲み込んでしまって
Swallowing the words stuck in my throat,
本当のことも隠して 嘘ついて
hiding the truth and telling lies,
声を潰した 心を殺して
crushing my voice, killing my heart...
つぎはぎの姿 生きていると言えるだろうか
In a patched-up form, can I really say I'm alive?
だから
That's why,
その手を握りしめてよ
hold tight onto that hand.
枯れるのを恐れては 耐えて
Fearing wilting, enduring,
枯れてしまうけど
even if it ends up wilting...
転ぶのを選び 傷が増えても
Even if I choose to stumble and gain more scars,
前に進むんじゃない
isn't moving forward what matters?
生きている本当の言葉を
The true words of living,
生きていることを
the fact that I am alive—
どうかその目に映して
please reflect it in your eyes.
また夢を見よう
Let's dream once more.
私も怖いけど
I'm scared too, but...
君がいれば
as long as I have you.
というわけで、皆さん、こんやっぴー！
So then, everyone, kon-yappi~!
はい！ホロライブ4期生の常闇トワです！イェーイ！
Hi! I'm Tokoyami Towa from Hololive 4th Gen! Yay!
ということで、本日は生誕祭...あ！
So, today is my Birthday Live... Ah!
今日はね、トワちゃんの誕生日なんです。ハッピーバースデー、トワ... to トワということで。
Today is Towa-chan's birthday! Happy Birthday to Towa... to Towa!
えー、お誕生日と！
Um, my birthday, and...
Andそして！
And also!
何回言うんだよって。なんと、新衣装のお披露目もあります！イェーイ！
"How many times are you gonna say that?" And we also have a new outfit reveal! Yay!
100万人記念を使って、新衣装を作っていただきました！
We used the 1 million subscriber milestone to have this new outfit made!
イェーイ！
Yay!
そしてね、今日のライブなんですが、ミニライブになっておりまして、
And as for today's live, it's a mini-live,
大体30分から40分ぐらいで終わるんじゃないかなと思ってるんですけども、
so I think it'll end in about 30 to 40 minutes,
その短い時間でも楽しんでいただければなと思います！よろしくお願いします！
but I hope you enjoy this short time! Please enjoy!
はい！
Alright!
で、今回は、スープさんという会社に手伝ってもらって、
So, this time, a company called SOOP helped us out,
今日のライブを作ってます！スープさん、ありがとう！
to create today's live! Thank you, SOOP!
そしてね、これ収録なんですけれども、
And also, this was pre-recorded,
収録の日に、スープさんから「常闇祭に応募したんですけど外れました」みたいなことを言われて...
but on the recording day, someone from SOOP told me, "I applied for Tokoyami Matsuri, but I didn't win the ticket raffle..."
「え、知らなかったんだけど応募してたの？」つって。もう何回もお世話になってるんですけどね。
I was like, "Eh? I had no idea, you applied?" even though we work with them all the time.
ちょっと、プチ笑いというか。
It was kind of a little funny moment.
ということで、今日はさっきも言った通り、
So today, as I mentioned earlier,
3Dの新衣装もありますし、
we have a new 3D outfit,
他にもなんと発表がありますので、
plus, what's more, we have an announcement!
ぜひ最後までここに居座り続けてください！
So please, stay tuned right here until the very end!
はい！
Alright!
で、そして、ハッシュタグのお知らせです！ピ！
Next, here's an announcement about the hashtag! Beep!
こちら！
This one right here!
はい！
Yep!
#常闇トワ生誕祭2026
#TokoyamiTowaBirthdayLive2026
になりますので、ぜひたくさん感想をポストしてくださいね！
will be the hashtag, so please post lots of your thoughts and impressions!
美人の写真のスクリーンショットも待ってますよ！
I'm also waiting for your screenshots of this beautiful girl!
はい！
Okay!
はい、で、えっと、曲の振り返りなんですが、
Right, now to recap the songs so far,
1曲目が『Saki-gake』！
the 1st song was "Saki-gake"!
を、1stソロライブの衣装を着て歌わせていただきました。
I sang it wearing my 1st Solo Live outfit.
そして、2曲目はですね、『不可視』を、
And for the 2nd song, I sang "Fukashi",
2ndソロライブの衣装で歌わせていただきました！イェーイ！
in my 2nd Solo Live outfit! Yay!
あの、そこまで意図してなかったんだけど、
Um, I didn't actually intend it to turn out this way,
どちらの曲もソロライブの一番最後、本当に最後の最後のアンコールの最後の曲だったんですよ！
but both songs were the very last track—literally the final song of the final encore of those solo lives!
どちらも好きだから入れただけなんですけど。
I just picked them because I love both songs, though.
はい。なんか、この収録をしてる時にどっちのソロライブの景色が思い浮かんで、ちょっとエモかったです。
Yeah. While recording this, the scenery from both solo lives came to mind, and it felt pretty emotional!
はい、ぜひBlu-rayも発売してるのでチェックしてくださいね！
Yes, the Blu-rays are available now, so please check them out!
はい！
Alright!
そして、次なんですけれども...
And next up...
なんと！先日ソロライブを終えた、あの超超超超大物ゲストと一緒に歌っちゃいます！
Surprisingly, I'll be singing with a super, super, super big guest who just finished her solo live recently!
えー、こちらは...
Uh, this is...
もう言っちゃうと、ねねねが来てくれます！
Well, to put it simply, Nene-ne is joining us!
ねねねとね、先日6月28日に、
With Nene-ne, back on June 28th,
なんと、ま、これ受け入れてる形にはなってるんだけど、
surprisingly—well, I kind of just accepted it, but—
ねねねトワはカップル4周年記念！
it was Nene-ne Towa's 4th Couple Anniversary!
ねねねトワは4周年記念になりまして、
It was Nene-ne Towa's 4th anniversary,
そこで！初めてオリ曲を出したんですよ！
and so, we released our very first original song!
その曲をね、今日はダンスフルバージョンでお届けしたいと思います！
Today, we'd like to perform that song for you in its full dance version!
『#ウチらしか勝たん』！どうぞ！
"#UchirashikaKatan"! Please enjoy!
盛れてる角度で切り取る今日も
Framing today at the best flattering angle,
それだけじゃちょっと物足りないでしょ？
but that alone feels a bit lacking, doesn't it?
Do you know? Place sticker, my...
smartphone, check it out!
褒賞 賛辞 もっと頂戴 はいはいこちらに注目
Give me more praise and compliments! Yes, yes, focus over here!
キュートなだけじゃ終われない
Just being cute isn't enough.
でも難しくない甘い罠
But it's a simple, sweet trap.
私をポップした画面ごしのサー
Sirs on the other side of the screen who clicked on me,
そう簡単にさ 触れさせはしないの
I won't let you touch me that easily.
ねえ こっちに来たいんでしょ？
Hey, you want to come over here, right?
隣にいてほしいんでしょ？
You want me to be by your side, right?
ねえ もっと見たいんでしょ？
Hey, you want to see more, right?
私がいんでしょ？
You want me, don't you?
完全優勝でしょ
Total victory, right?
まだまだ足りない 私への Like
Still not enough likes for me!
単純明快な世界
A simple and clear world,
いやまだ足りない もらい足りない
No, still not enough, haven't gotten enough!
勝たん 勝たん 勝たん 私しか勝たん
Win, win, win! I'm the best, I win!
勝たん 勝たん 勝たん ウチらが勝たん
Win, win, win! We are the best, we win!
勝たん 勝たん 勝たん 私しか勝たん
Win, win, win! I'm the best, I win!
勝たん 勝たん 勝たん ウチらが勝たん
Win, win, win! We are the best, we win!
堕ちてくライトで塗り替える今日
Today is repainted by falling lights,
でも綺麗なだけじゃ Oh no, no
But just being pretty is oh no, no.
つまんないでしょ 想像以上の Show
That'd be boring, right? A show beyond imagination,
期待以上を見せてほしいの
I want you to show me even more than I expect.
ねえ もっと近づきたいんでしょ？
Hey, you want to get closer, right?
本音まで知りたいんでしょ？
You want to know my true feelings, right?
ねえ 目と目反らせないんでしょ？
Hey, you can't look away from my eyes, right?
私しかいないんでしょ？
There's no one else for you but me, right?
断然本命でしょ
Definitely your favorite, right?
まだまだ足りない 私への Like
Still not enough likes for me!
絶対運命でしょ
Absolute destiny, right?
いやまだ足りない 愛足りない
No, still not enough, not enough love!
その目を深く見つめたいの その熱ごと欲しくなるの
I want to gaze deep into those eyes, I want to make all that passion mine.
ねえ 計算はいらないの ねえ 本当を聞かせて
Hey, no need for calculating, hey, tell me the truth.
完全優勝でしょ
Total victory, right?
まだまだ足りない 私への Like
Still not enough likes for me!
絶対運命でしょ
Absolute destiny, right?
いやまだ足りない 愛足りない
No, still not enough, not enough love!
全然足りない もらい足りない
Not at all enough, haven't gotten enough!
勝たん 勝たん 勝たん 私しか勝たん
Win, win, win! I'm the best, I win!
勝たん 勝たん 勝たん ウチらが勝たん
Win, win, win! We are the best, we win!
勝たん 勝たん 勝たん 私しか勝たん
Win, win, win! I'm the best, I win!
勝たん 勝たん 勝たん ウチらが勝たん
Win, win, win! We are the best, we win!
はい！ということで、ねねねとわで『ウチらが勝たん』でした！
Yes! So that was "Uchiraga Katan" by NeneNeneTowa!
いかがだったでしょうか？ダンス頑張りました！ねね、ありがとう！
How was it? We worked hard on the dance! Nene, thank you!
はい、ちょっとギャルっぽい感じで 振り付けも愛莉先生に作ってもらいました！
Yeah! It's a bit gal-ish, and the choreography was created by Airi-sensei!
もともと「勝たん勝たん」が結構好きで このピースのところ「勝たん勝たん勝たん」
I've always really liked the "katan katan" part, especially this peace sign section: "Katan, katan, katan."
これがギャルっぽくて可愛くてすごく好きです
This is so gal-like and cute, I love it!
ぜひ踊ってみてね！……踊ってみてね、むずいな。
Please try dancing it! ...Though saying "try dancing it" is kind of hard.
はい、ぜひいっぱい繰り返し見てもらえればなと思います 曲も聴いてね！はい。
Anyway, I hope you watch it over and over again! Listen to the song too! Yep.
ということで、お待たせいたしました！
So, thank you for waiting!
この後は...
Up next...
常闇トワちゃん 新3D...あ、違う！3D新衣装の発表！
Tokoyami Towa's new 3D... Ah, wait! The reveal of my new 3D outfit!
ということで、着替えていきたいと思います！
So I'm going to go change my outfit!
着替えます！
I'm changing!
じゃ、着替えますからね！着替えますからね！
Ah, well, I'm changing, okay? I'm changing!
よいしょ、よいしょと。
Yoisho, yoisho...
はぁ... 大変だ。
Phew... That's tough.
すごい、やっぱり衣装...うわー！うおー！
Wow, as expected, the outfit... Woah! Woah!
どんなだよ、ということで着替えました！
"What is this even?" Anyway, I'm changed!
では、いいですか？いきますよ、皆さん！
Now then, are you ready? Here it comes, everyone!
いきますよ！なんかザーボンさん・ドドリアさん来た！
Here we go! Wait, Zarbon and Dodoria showed up!
あ、やばい！美しい脚が！美しい脚が出ております！
Ah, oh no! Beautiful legs! Beautiful legs are appearing!
バランスが取りづらい
It's hard to balance!
どう？ほら、まずこの脚！
How is it? Look, first, these legs!
これ最近の流行りじゃない？この薄々の靴下
Isn't this super trendy recently? These sheer socks.
これ名前何ていうのか分かんないけど
I don't know what they're called though.
新衣装、さえきやひろ先生に描いていただいたんですけども
Saeki Yahiro-sensei designed this new outfit for me,
先生のセンスが良すぎて 私にはこの名前が何なのか分からないんですが
and Sensei's taste is so great that I don't even know what these are called,
でもこんな感じに脚はなってますよ！イラストレーターの皆さん、必見でございます！
but this is what my legs look like! Illustrators, this is a must-see!
でもってリボンも可愛くない？ほら！
And aren't these ribbons cute too? Look!
あ、いいですねカメラさん、いいですね！ほらほら！
Ah, nice camera work, Mr. Camera! Nice! Look, look!
はい、じゃあだんだん上に上がって...
Okay, now slowly panning up...
ちょっとスカートの... あ、やべえスカートって言っちゃった。あ、スカートじゃない。のところまで...
Up to... Oh shoot, I said skirt. Ah, it's not a skirt. Up to here...
やー！ストップ！
Yaaah! Stop!
はい！スカート... こんな感じになってます。
Okay! The skirt... it looks like this.
スカートというか、これなんて言うか... 一応ズボンなんですよねー。
Or rather, what should I call this... It's technically shorts.
はい。で、見てー！可愛くない？
Yes. And look! Isn't this cute?
ビビ... ビビのキーホルダーだ！むにゃむにゃむにゃむにゃ...
Bibi... A Bibi keychain! *squish squish squish*
可愛い！むにゃむにゃむにゃむにゃ...
So cute! *squish squish squish*
はい、キーホルダーがついてたりとか...
Yep, it has a keychain attached...
ちゃんと尻尾が出れるようになってたりとか...
And there's a slit for my tail to come out...
しております。そして見てください！
...and so on. And please take a look!
ネイル！と指輪！
My nails! And rings!
アクセサリー。ほら、こんな感じです。
Accessories. See, they look like this.
ねー、ギャルで可愛いでしょー？
Right? It's gal-style and cute, isn't it?
イェーイ！
Yay!
はい、で、これで多分みんなスクリーンショットしたから...
Okay, so with this, everyone probably took a screenshot...
意外とトワのネイル真似する人いっぱいいるんですよ。だから...
Surprisingly, lots of people copy Towa's nail art. So...
このネイルを多分真似してくれるでしょう！
I bet people will copy this nail art too!
はい、ということで、ちょっと見えてきちゃってますけれども、もうちょっと首のところまで...
Alright, so you can see a bit already, but up to the neck area...
じゃ、あげてあげて... ドン！
Now, move up, move up... Bam!
うわー！やばい！髪の毛が... なんか長くなーい？ちょっと髪の毛長くなーい？
Uwaah! Oh no! The hair... Isn't it kinda long? Isn't my hair a bit longer?
なんかちょっとおばさんみたいな言い方になってる。
I sound a bit like an old lady saying that.
はい、で、これがジャケットですね。ジャケットに、ちょっと透け感があるトップスに、ということで...
Alright, and this is the jacket. A jacket over a slightly sheer top, so...
はい、腕には「TOWA」と...「常闇トワ」と書いてあります。
Yes, on the arm it says "TOWA"... and "Tokoyami Towa".
こっちは何にもない。
There's nothing on this side.
はい、ちょっと後ろ見ちゃうと... うわっ！
Okay, taking a look at the back... Woah!
なんか... ストレートじゃない？髪の毛が。
Isn't my hair... straight?
ということで、上まで行っちゃいますか！
So, shall we go all the way up?
はい、ドン！
Alright, bam!
じゃーん！ということで、帽子持っていたりして！
Ta-da! So, I'm wearing a cap!
こんな感じです！イェーイ！
It looks like this! Yay!
はい、どうでしょう？
Alright, how is it?
はい、今、撮るところですよー。
Okay, now's the time to take screenshots.
はい、撮るところですよー！イェーイ！
Yep, time to take photos! Yay!
はい！
Alright!
そう、今回キャップ... キャップなんです。
Yeah, this time it's a cap... A cap.
ちょっとストリート系というか何というか...
It's kinda street style or something like that...
でしょ？で、あとは...
Right? And also...
こっちだ。
Over here.
ギャルっぽい！キラキラ付いてます！
Very gal-esque! It's got shiny sparkly stuff!
これもセンスが高すぎてよく分かってないけど付いてるやつ！
This too, the design sense is so high I don't fully get it, but it's attached!
最悪だよ自分についてんのに。
That's terrible of me, since it's on myself.
センスが指しすごすぎるんですよねー。いつも... あの、デザインしてもらうとびっくりします、おしゃれすぎて。
The design sense is just amazing. Every time I get designs made, I'm amazed because they're so stylish.
であとちょっとカッコいいめのパールとチェーンのネックレス付けたりとかしております。
And I'm also wearing a cool pearl and chain necklace, and so on.
裏はこんな感じ。
The back looks like this.
はい。
Yep.
では！なんと！この帽子... 取れちゃうんです！
Now then! Believe it or not! This cap... can actually come off!
ちょっと帽子取ってきますね。
I'll go take off the cap real quick.
取れました、帽子！
I took off the cap!
凄いでしょ？
Amazing, right?
もう日差しを直接受けてしまいます。
Now I'm directly exposed to sunlight.
っていうのは置いといて、はい！白いね、メッシュが付いてたりとか、このキラキラしてるのが付いてたりとか...
Setting that aside, yes! There are white mesh highlights, and these sparkly bits...
あと、今回はハーフ... ハーフアップというかハーフアップじゃないけどこれ、三つ編みで...
Also, this time it's half... half-up, or not quite half-up, but with these braids...
編み込みしてもらって後ろ... 可愛く結んでます。こんな感じです。
...braided in, and at the back, it's tied up nicely. It looks like this.
これちゃんとね、イラストレーターさんのみんながファーって描いてくれるの楽しみに懸けてるんでゆっくり見せてます。
I'm showing it slowly because I'm really looking forward to all the illustrators drawing fan art of it.
あとは、もういつも通りピアスがバチバチ付いてたりしてます！
And as usual, I have a bunch of piercings attached!
はい！
Yep!
で、今ちょっとまだジャケット着てるんですけれど...
And right now I'm still wearing the jacket, but...
このジャケットを脱ぐと... あ、脱ぐことができるんですよ。脱ぐとどうなるか見せたいと思います！
When I take off this jacket... Ah, I can take it off! I want to show you what it looks like without it!
この... この名残り惜しく出るのにハマってるのかもしれない。
I might be addicted to making a lingering exit like this.
うわー！
Uwaah!
えー... この叫び声。
Uh... that scream.
あ、こんな感じです！この...
Ah, it looks like this! This...
えー20kgあるジャケットを脱ぎました！あ、帽子は30kgありました。すごい今首が軽いー！
Uh, I took off the 20kg jacket! Ah, the cap was 30kg. My neck feels so light now!
ということで、こんな感じー！
So, this is how it looks!
このさ、トワがワーワー言ってる間ね、スタジオはすっごいシーンとしてるからすっごい恥ずかしいんだよ？
You know, while Towa is talking noisily, the studio is dead silent, so it's super embarrassing, you know?
はい、見てください！
Yes, please take a look!
腕のアクセサリーがこんな感じで...
The arm accessories look like this...
しかも... タトゥーがここに入っちゃってます！
And also... I have a tattoo right here!
そして...
And...
こっち。
...over here.
こっちもカッコいいアクセサリーを腕につけております。
I'm wearing cool accessories on this arm too.
はい、で、こんな感じです！
Yep, and it looks like this!
はい、これでも写真撮ってくださいね！イェーイ、はい！
Alright, take photos of this too, okay? Yay, alright!
イェーイ！あ！
Yay! Ah!
分かった
I get it.
これや！まず、はい！
This is it! First, here!
これね！写真撮ってね、みんな！
This, okay? Take pictures, everyone!
はい！
Here!
T
あ、Tじゃない。これ言っちゃダメだ、これ。あ、ピ！はい！
Ah, not T! I shouldn't say this. Bleep! Okay!
こんな感じでーす！イェーイ！
It's like this! Yay!
後ろも
The back too!
はい、こんな感じ。スッキリするよね？
Yes, like this. Looks refreshing, right?
ジャケットないだけで
Just without the jacket.
はい！で、まださらにあるんです。
Yes! And there's even more.
実は、この上、黒のトップス...
Actually, this black top...
色変わるんです。虹色に。
The color changes. To rainbow color!
ちょっと待っててください。
Please wait a moment.
えーっと、塗り替えて、と。
Umm, repainting it...
で、もう終わったから...
And now that it's done...
うわ、出てきた！
Whoa, here I am!
はい！
Okay!
ジャジャーン！虹色ではないでーす！
Ta-da! It's not rainbow-colored!
白でーす！
It's white!
だから、上と下、白々にする事ができるんですよね。
So you can make both top and bottom all white!
はい、どうでしょう？
Yes, how is it?
で、まだね、他にも実は組み合わせがあるんで、
And well, there are actually other combinations too...
どの組み合わせが良かったのか、後で教えてください。
So please tell me later which combination was best.
はい！で、あ、これスクショしてくださいね！はい、はいスクショタイム！
Okay! And please screenshot this! Screenshot time!
この時点で何をしたいのかが分かった人...
Those who figured out what I want to do at this point...
静かにですよー！
Stay quiet, okay!
はい！
Okay!
では！そしてね、なんと！
Now! And surprisingly...
下もね！
The bottom too!
実は...変わるんですよ！
Actually... changes!
シュールすぎる！たまには反対側帰れよ！みたいな感じだけど。
Too surreal! Feels like "go back to the other side for once!" though.
はい！
Okay!
ジャジャジャジャジャーン！
Ta-da-da-da-da!
じゃん！黒色ー！
Ta-da! Black color!
じゃん！こっちが白で、こっちが黒。どうでしょう？
Ta-da! White here, black here. How is it?
最初とは違う色になってますけれど。
It's a different color from the start, but...
ま、黒白で、でもね、かっこいい感じ、シンプルだけどかっこいいみたいな感じで...
Well, black and white looks cool, simple yet cool...
色違いも作ってもらいましたー！
I also had color variations made!
イェーイ！
Yay!
あ、スクショタイムだよね！
Ah, screenshot time, right!
さっき、こう...こう出来たから...
Earlier, I could do this... like this...
こう？
Like this?
え、こう？
Wait, like this?
ダサすぎる！
Too uncool!
なんか、いいように、してください！
Please make it look good somehow!
イェーイ！
Yay!
あんな感じでね！
Like that!
えー、ということで、だから上も白黒、下も白黒ということでね、
So, both the top and bottom can be white or black,
上と下でね、白、黒、白、黒でね、好きな組み合わせにできる衣装になっております！
so you can mix and match white and black top and bottom into your favorite combination!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much!
はい！
Okay!
では、じゃあ最初のに服に戻ろうかな？
Now, shall I go back to the original outfit?
少々お待ちください。
Please wait a moment.
ふぅ、この30kgの帽子と20kgのジャケットを着て...
Phew, putting on this 30kg hat and 20kg jacket...
で、服も塗り替えてまた、ペンキベタベタで戻ってきて...
And repainting the clothes again, coming back all sticky with paint...
ふぅ！
Phew!
はい、ということで！
Okay, so!
最後...あ、ちょっと待って、最後ね、はい、これ。
Lastly... ah wait, lastly, yeah, this.
最後、こう...こうか？こうじゃない？
At the end, like... like this? Isn't it like this?
え、こう？
Wait, like this?
ま、いいようにしてください。
Well, please use it however you like!
ということで、いっぱい、各色違いにスクリーンショットゾーンを撮ったんですけど、
So, I took screenshot moments for each color variation,
どうでしたか？
how was it?
Towaという文字を作りました！
I made the letters TOWA!
ぜひ！ぜひどうぞ！
Please! Go right ahead!
何を？何をどうぞって感じなんだけど。
What? "Go right ahead with what?" is how I feel, but...
まあ、ということでこんな感じで新衣装はこう言う風になっております！
Well anyway, this is what the new outfit looks like!
イェーイ！いっぱいね、ファートとかね！
Yay! Lots of posts and stuff!
いっぱい書いてくれたら嬉しいです！
I'd be happy if you post a lot!
いつもありがとうございます！
Thank you as always!
ということで！この後は、嬉しいお知らせとなります！
So! Up next, we have some exciting announcements!
常闇トワ誕生記念2026のグッズ販売決定！
Tokoyami Towa Birthday Celebration 2026 merch launch confirmed!
イェーイ！
Yay!
こちらの配信後に販売開始となりますので、概要欄をチェックして待っててくださいね！
Sales will start after this stream, so check the description box and stay tuned!
ということで！
So!
気になるグッズの詳細は、こちらをご覧ください！どうぞ！
For details on the merchandise, please take a look here! Go ahead!
うわー！うわー！
Woah! Woah!
よいしょと。ということで...
Up we go. So...
イラストは、みゃむ先生に描き下ろしていただきましたー！
The illustration was drawn by Myamu-sensei!
イェーイ！
Yay!
かわいいでしょ、これ！
Isn't this cute?!
旅行、お出かけをイメージして描いてもらいまして、
It was drawn with a travel/going-out theme in mind,
今回の新衣装をモチーフとして、新衣装で描いてもらいました！
and it features the new outfit as its theme!
そしてね、灯籠祭りやランタン祭り大好きなので、そちらをモチーフにしてもらってます。
And since I love lantern festivals, that was also used as a motif.
よし！ということで、こっから立ってね...よいしょと。
Alright! So standing up from here... heave-ho.
お待たせいたしました！
Thank you for waiting!
はい！ということで、この後...というか...
Yes! So, after this... or rather...
アイテムを呼び出していきたいと思います
I'd like to introduce the items!
まずはこちら！どうぞ！ドン！
First up is this! Here you go! Bam!
ブン！「願いを込めて。LEDアートパネル」！イェーイ！
Boom! "Wish Upon a Star: LED Art Panel"! Yay!
このね、MY描先生に描き下ろしてもらったイラストを使って
Using this illustration drawn by MYAO-sensei,
えー、アートパネルを作っちゃいました！
um, we made an art panel!
なんとこのアートパネル、LEDが入っておりますので
And guess what! This art panel has LEDs built into it,
ふんわり光っちゃいまーす！
so it glows softly!
ちょっと美しい感じでしょ？
Looks pretty classy, right?
ぜひこの機会に手に入れてくださいね！
Please be sure to get your hands on one during this opportunity!
はい！そして2つ目はこちら！ボーン！
Alright! And the second item is this! Bam!
「どっちのトワにする？リバーシブル アクリルスタンド」！
"Which Towa Will You Choose? Reversible Acrylic Stand"!
はい！こちらもですね、この新衣装の撮り下ろしとなっておりまして
Yes! This one is also a newly taken illustration of my new outfit,
さっき色々帽子付けたりとか、上が黒、下が黒、上白、下白みたいな色違いを見せたと思うんですけども
earlier I showed various color variations like putting on the cap, or black top/black bottom, white top/white bottom,
それをね、ちゃんと表現してるアクリルスタンドになっております！
and this acrylic stand properly recreates all of those!
表のトワちゃん！裏のトワちゃん！どっちのトワにする？
Front Towa-chan! Back Towa-chan! Which Towa will you choose?
ということで、こちらも楽しんでみてくださいね！
So please look forward to this one as well!
はい！そして続いてはこちら！
Alright, moving on to the next item!
はい！「新衣装モチーフ キーホルダー」！イェーイ！
Yes! "New Outfit Motif Keychain"! Yay!
見てください！これです、これ！
Take a look! It's this, right here!
このトワのビビと、ほら！ほら！「TOWA」と書いたこのキーホルダーが、
This Bibi of Towa's, and look! Look! This keychain that says "TOWA"...
このキーホルダーが… 本来ここにあったアクセサリーがキーホルダーになっちゃいまーす！イェーイ！
This keychain... the accessory that was originally right here became a keychain! Yay!
はい！このモチーフにしてますので、ぜひお揃いで手に入れてみてください！
Yes! Since it's modeled after this motif, please get one to match with me!
パーツはね、それぞれ取り外し可能となっております。よろしくお願いいたします！
Each of the parts can be detached. Please check it out!
はい！そして最後はこちら！ボーン！
Okay, and the final item is this! Bam!
「トワ様とお揃いキャップ」！イェーイ！
"Matching Cap with Towa-sama"! Yay!
このね、帽子とお揃いのキャップを発売することになりましたー！
We're releasing a cap that matches this hat of mine!
普段使いしやすいデザインにもなってますので
It's designed to be easy to wear for everyday use as well,
ぜひ「今日トワとお揃いの帽子を付けたいな」って方は購入してみてください！お願いします！
so if you feel like "I want to wear a matching hat with Towa today!", please consider buying one! Thank you!
はい！ということで、そんな感じかな？紹介は。
Alright! So I guess that's about it for the merchandise showcase.
あ！そうだった！戻る前に！
Oh! That's right! Before we move on!
この全部を買った「フルセット特典」…あ、「フルセット購入特典」もあります！忘れておりました！
There's also a "Full Set Purchase Bonus" for buying all of these! I almost forgot!
フルセットをご購入していただいた皆さんには、箔押し複製サインと、あと今回はメッセージ入りポストカードをプレゼントしたいと思います！
For everyone who purchases the full set, we'll be including a postcard with a foil-stamped replica autograph and a special message!
ぜひフルセットで購入してみてください！
Please consider getting the full set!
はい！よろしくお願いいたします！
Yes! Thank you so much!
はい、で、こっから…あ、そうだ！
Alright, and from here... Oh, that's right!
ここもまだここにいて… なんとこれだけじゃないんですよ！グッズだけじゃなくて…
I'm still staying right here, because that's not all! It's not just the merch...
あ、グッズは概要欄もチェックしてほしいのと、あと…
Oh, please check the description section for details on the merch! And also...
そうなんです！最初のね、配信の最初に言ったと思うんですけれども、
That's right! As I mentioned at the very beginning of the stream,
お知らせが、まだ1個あるんですよ！
there's still one more announcement!
はい！そのお知らせとは…こちら！ボーン！
Yes! And that announcement is... this! Bam!
新曲「SMASH IT UP」が、この後24時から、0時になった瞬間からデジタルリリースされます！
My new song "SMASH IT UP" will be released digitally starting tonight at 24:00, right as the clock strikes midnight!
イェーイ！
Yay!
いつもね、トワの楽曲とかつくる時にすごくお世話になってる磯野さんっていう方がいらっしゃるんですけど、磯野さんにね、書き下ろしていただきました！
I've been working with Isono-san, who always helps me out when making Towa's songs, and he composed this brand-new track for me!
なんかその結構ざっくり「トワっぽい曲でお願いします」って…
I gave a pretty rough request like, "Please make a very Towa-like song,"
結構お世話になってるんですよ。だからトワの音域とか、どういうのが得意かっていうのを知ってくださってるので、じゃあそれを最大級に活かしたようなトワの曲を作ってくださいって言って出来た曲が「SMASH IT UP」なんですよね！
because he's been working with me so much. Since he knows my vocal range and what style suits me best, I asked him to make a Towa song that brings out my full potential, and "SMASH IT UP" was born!
うん！
Mm-hmm!
結構ね、でも来た時は、「トワ歌えるかな？トワっぽいかな？あ、でもこういうイメージ抱いてるんだな」っていう風な感じで、すごい面白かったです！
When I first received it, I was like, "Can Towa really sing this? Is this really Towa-like? Oh, so this is how he envisions me!" It was super interesting!
でもね、取るまでは不安だったんですよ、最初取るまでは。でも取ってみたらすごい自分に合っててかっこいい曲になったので、ぜひ購入して聴いていただければなと思います！ダウンロードしてみてください！
I was actually feeling anxious until I recorded it. But once I recorded it, it fit me so well and turned out to be such a cool song, so I really hope you buy it and listen to it! Please download it!
はい！
Yes!
はい！じゃあね…
Alright! Well then...
「じゃあどんな曲なんだよ」って、「そんなのゼロでダウンロードなんて出来ないよ」って思うじゃないですか！
You might be thinking, "Well, what kind of song is it?" or "I can't just download it blindly!" right?
いやいや！今日はその…この発表した新曲で、本日のライブを締めくくりたいと…
No, no! Today, I'd like to close out today's live stream with this newly announced track...
えっと、ここカットして…
Um, please cut this part out...
「ここカットして」って言ってたけどカットしなくていいですからね！
I said "cut this part out," but you don't actually have to cut it, okay?
はい！では、そんな新曲で本日のライブを締めくくりたいと思います！
Alright! With that said, I'd like to conclude today's live stream with my new song!
いいですか？
Are you ready?
では、本日最後の曲です！
Now then, here is the final song of the day!
聞いてください
Please listen.
SMASH IT UP
熱に充てられ
Driven by the heat,
熱を与えて
granting heat,
シンクロしていく
synchronizing,
イズム誇れ
be proud of your ideology.
くだらないボーダー
Foolish borders,
SMASH IT UP
溶けるように
As if melting away,
混ざり合っていく本能通り性
instinctively blending together.
始めよう最高
Let's begin the ultimate
再構築 スポットライト頂戴
reconstruction—give me the spotlight!
プロトタイプはいらない
I don't need a prototype,
根拠なら目の前に
the proof is right in front of you.
一人残さず巻き込むライオット
A riot dragging everyone along without leaving anyone behind.
貫く覚悟
A determination to push through,
限界玉砕しちゃうわ
shattering through my limits completely.
日和ってる暇なんてない
There's no time to hesitate!
歌う繊細 豪快 自在に
Singing delicately, grandly, and freely,
世界が無視できないくらい
so much that the world can't ignore it!
影ごと照らして
Illuminating even the shadows,
強くあれ
be strong!
前前のめりなBPM
An eager, forward-leaning BPM,
狂気じみたプライド抱いて
holding onto a maddening pride,
くだらないボーダー
foolish borders,
SMASH IT UP
凝り固まった価値観
Rigid, set-in-stone values—
壊せ 壊せ 壊せ 壊せ
break them, break them, break them, break them!
絵空事だった確信
A conviction that was once a pipe dream—
創る 創る 創る
create it, create it, create it!
グラついた心境
An unstable state of mind,
揺れ動いた心境も
even feelings that waver,
手懐けろ大交響曲
tame them, grand symphony!
絡み合うコード
Entangled chords...
奏でる独壇場
Playing on my exclusive stage!
答えはここになんねんだって歌うの
Singing that the answer has been right here all along!
貫く覚悟
A determination to push through,
限界玉砕しちゃうわ
shattering through my limits completely.
日和ってる暇なんてない
There's no time to hesitate!
歌う繊細 豪快 自在に
Singing delicately, grandly, and freely,
世界が無視できないくらい
so much that the world can't ignore it!
影ごと照らして
Illuminating even the shadows,
強くあれ
be strong!
前前のめりなBPM
An eager, forward-leaning BPM,
狂気じみたプライド抱いて
holding onto a maddening pride,
くだらないボーダー
foolish borders—
なんざ
what of them?
SMASH IT UP
Woah-oh-oh